Alfred Boateng

Full Stack Developer

Kumasi Box ks 14551 kwadwo.boateng.alfred@gmail.com +233541034798

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with a wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of the process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 3 years of related experience.

Sponsorship required to work in the US

Work Experience

Full Stack Developer

Kuubix Global - London January 2023 to Present

- Coordinated deployments of new software, feature updates, and fixes.
- Supervised work of programmers, designers, and technicians, assigned tasks, and monitoring performance against targets.
- Analyzed existing software implementations to identify areas requiring improvement.
- Managed over 10 developers per day.
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs, and enhancements.
- Conducted data modeling, performance, and integration testing.
- Tested and deployed scalable and highly available software products.
- Worked with back-end developers to design APIs

Full Stack Web Developer

BH-IC, LLC dba (To Be Determined) - Remote September 2022 to January 2023

- Worked with back-end developers to design APIs.
- · Developed and maintained microservices architectures using Docker, Kubernetes, and OpenShift.
- Used Node.JS, ORM, and SQL/No-SQL to develop and manage databases.
- Boosted network, system, and data availability and integrity through preventive maintenance and upgrades.
- Designed testing protocols to locate issues within system.
- Used Javascript, SQL, and HTML to develop app solutions.
- Collaborated with fellow engineers to evaluate software and hardware interfaces.

Full Stack Developer

Self Employed Contractor - Accra January 2020 to September 2022

Developed technical solutions required to accommodate specific user-facing assets

- Pulled from PHP, SQL, JavaScript, and other back-end library knowledge to bolster programming resources.
- Provided security maintenance and patching on website interface to maintain viability after launch.
- Implemented Google-based SEO and ad campaigns to meet budget specifications.
- Coded websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and jQuery languages.
- Adhered to SEO best practices while designing sites.
- Multi-tasked across multiple functions and roles to meet deadlines and organizational expectations.
- Engaged with clients to plan and optimize site issues and queries.
- Discussed site and app requirements with clients to produce actionable development plans.
- Applied emerging technologies to update and maintain site applicability.
- Projects completed include christmodel.academy and aurageospatial.com

Mentor (Volunteer)

April 2022 to July 2022

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on maintaining motivation in the program.

Full Stack Developer Intern

Kraado - Accra

June 2021 to January 2022

- Worked with senior developers and designers to implement Software using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React.
- Boosted web traffic by improving navigation and rectifying bottlenecks.
- Cultivated good working relationships with clients, strategic partners and internal teams and explained technical concepts clearly to internal and external audiences.
- Conceived and built optimized landing pages in HTML and CSS for integration and cross-browser compatibility.
- Completed full redesigns of existing websites to improve navigation, enhance visuals and strengthen search engine rankings.
- Increased sales by 10%.
- Crafted SEO strategy and intuitive interface for site to achieve prominent rankings across top browser platforms
- Employed coding practices based on commonly accepted standards to establish site layout and user interface
- Monitored technical performance of internal systems and gathered information from consumers about program functionality
- Collaborated with in-house web designers to create sleek and innovative UI design
- Developed, coded, modified and debugged application programs of varying degree of complexity with full independence
- Helped code and test software based web application software based on Agile Scrum and Kanban approaches
- Developed user-friendly web forms with validation and error handling

Education

Certificate in Web Development in Web Development

Microverse Coding Bootcamp - Remote

March 2022 to January 2023

Skills

- JavaScript
- React
- Redux
- jQuery
- HTML5
- CSS3

Back-End: Ruby

- Rails
- Node.js

• MySQL Tools & Methods: Git

- GitHub
- Heroku
- Netlify
- Mobile/Responsive Development
- RSpec
- TDD
- Chrome Dev Tools Professional: Remote Pair-Programming
- Teamwork
- Mentoring
- Agile
- AWS
- JSON
- User Interface (UI)
- REST
- Bootstrap
- APIs
- XML

Languages

• English - Fluent

Links

https://alfredboateng.netlify.app/

https://github.com/learnwithalfred

https://medium.com/@learnwithalfred

https://www.linkedin.com/in/learnwithalfred

https://www.youtube.com/@learnwithalfred